上 上 上
Go, go, go.
嫌犯逃入了一间仓库 正在全力追捕
Suspect on foot, entering warehouse. In pursuit.
上
Go.
别动 站在原地 放下武器
Freeze! Stop right there! Put down the weapon!
你们现在不能阻止的
You can't stop it now.
- 什么都阻止不了 - 趴在地上
- Nothing can stop it. - On the ground!
趴在地上 扔掉它 马上
On the ground. Drop it, right now!
哈洛伦 哈洛伦警探
Halloran. Detective halloran.
如果他17分钟内没赶来这里
If he's not here in 17 minutes,
就有5个人会死
five people are going to die.
快让哈洛伦过来
Get halloran here, now!
哈洛伦在他妈哪呢？
Where the fuck is halloran?
会有人送命的
People are gonna die, man!
他还不知道吗？
Doesn't he know?
全部后退
All of you, get back.
- 哈洛伦 - 埃德加
- Halloran! - Edgar!
埃德加 你他妈这是在干什么？
Edgar, what the fuck are you doing?
- 你快把遥控器放下 - 我不能这么做
- You put down that remote. - I can't.
- 那是干什么用的？- 游戏已经开始了
- What's that for? - The games are just getting started.
- 什么游戏？- 他的游戏 他的规则
- What game? - His games, his rules.
我得选择谁死 他们还是我
I gotta choose who dies. Them or me.
埃德加 我不想开枪 不代表我不会
Edgar, I don't want to shoot you, but I will.
放下遥控器
Drop the remote.
- 我瞄准他了 要开枪吗 - 不 不 不
- I got him, should I take it? - No, no, no.
瞄准遥控器 如果他有任何危险举动
Target the remote. If he moves to trigger it,
就打爆它
blow it to shit.
没有时间了
Running out of time!
- 那还有谁？- 埃德加
- Who else is there? - Edgar!
告诉我们这到底是怎么回事
Tell us what's going on!
谁在遥控你？
Who's controlling you?
我他妈可不想死
I'm not fucking dying.
是哪个傻逼往他胸口开枪的？
Which one of you assholes shot him in the chest?
游戏
The game.
已经开始了
It's started...
《电锯惊魂8：竖锯》
这是什么？
What is this?
这他妈是怎么回事？
What the hell? What the fuck?
这他妈什么情况？
Yo, what the hell?
- 妈的 - 天啊
- Oh, shit. - Oh, god.
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
不 不 不…
No, no, no...
这不是真的
This can't be happening!
来人啊 救命啊
Someone, help me!
不 不 不…
No, no, no...
救命 谁来救救我
Help! Somebody please help me.
救救我吧
Please, help me!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
求求你 救救我
Please, help me!
你别他妈过来
Just stay the fuck back!
你们现在肯定很诧异
I'm sure you are all wondering
为什么你们会在这里
why you're here.
毫无疑问 你们都否认自己有罪
You deny culpability, no doubt,
相信你们对现下的处境已有所了解 在这里
for the circumstances in which you find yourselves.
你们将得到救赎
Salvation can be yours,
前提是你们必须洗心革面
if you cleanse yourselves
你们惯于说谎 所以才会有如今的境遇
of the habitual lies which have brought you here.
你们欺骗自己
Lies that you have told yourselves,
欺骗他人且对其造成了深深的伤害
lies that have brutalized others.
忏悔吧 真实的话语能换回你们的自由
Confess. The truth will set you free.
但任何企图
But any attempt
违反我的规则的人 都会死
to violate my rules will kill you.
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
去你妈的
Fuck you!
首先 血之献祭
First, an offering of blood,
无论献祭血量多少
no matter how little,
头套上的灯会变成绿色
will give you a green light
只有这样才能活着逃离这个房间
to escape from this room with your lives.
如果你们把真实的自己从心魔中释放出来
If you can release yourself from your demons,
你们才可以除掉
you can begin to shed the chains
心魔附在你们身上的铁链
that those demons bring with them.
遵循我规则去做血之献祭
Make the simple blood sacrifice that I've requested,
或者面对严重的后果
or face severe consequences.
你们自己选择
The choice is yours.
这他妈到底是怎么回事？
The fuck is going on over here?
- 不 不 不… - 不 不要
- No, no, no... - No, no, no!
不
No!
不要
No! No!
我们该怎么办？该怎么办？
What do we do? What do we do?
谁有办法啊
Someone do something!
嘿 快醒醒
Hey! Wake up!
快醒醒
Wake up!
"血之献祭"
"An offering of blood..."
"无论血量多少"
"No matter how little..."
"血之献祭…"
"An offering of blood..."
割伤自己 你们得割伤自己
Cut yourself! You need to cut yourself!
给他血 我们就自由了
He wants blood and then you're free!
割伤自己 他要的是血
Cut yourself, he wants blood!
快割伤自己
Cut yourself!
操
Fuck!
来吧 就割一小下
Come on, come on, come on.
天啊 终于解脱了
Yes! Holy shit...
你得割伤自己…
You need to cut yourself!
这他妈…
What the...
不…
No...
割伤自己
Cut yourself!
你得割伤你自己
You need to cut yourself!
快割伤自己
Cut yourself!
我们这他妈是在哪？
Where the fuck are we?
他按了遥控器 却没见任何东西被启动
He hit the remote, but nothing triggered.
就目前我们的了解来看 是没有
As far as we know.
你觉得他说的游戏是真的吗？
You think the game's real?
不确定
Don't know.
他要求你到现场这事 你怎么看？
And why do you think he asked for you?
我们是老熟人了
We're good friends.
我两次把他送进监狱
I put him away twice.
埃德加·曼森是个反社会的瘾君子
Edgar munsen is a sociopathic meth head.
因故意伤人 持械抢劫 毒品交易
Been in and out of prison for assault and battery,
成了监狱的常客
armed robbery, drug dealing.
极品吧
Nice guy.
医生 把他叫醒吧 我们有问题问他
Doc, we need him awake. We've got questions.
抱歉 警探
Sorry, detective.
子弹就离心脏差一点
The bullet's lodged against the heart.
我用巴比妥使他进入昏迷状态 直到他病情稳定
I've got him in a barbiturate-induced coma until he stabilizes.
- 要多久？- 他得先消肿
- How long? - Swelling has to come down first.
两个小时 两个星期 我可说不准
Two hours. Two weeks. I can't tell you.
失陪了
Excuse me.
列个嫌疑人名单
Start the suspect list
从曼森的同伙们着手
with munsen's known associates.
看来这事情没那么简单
This is not gonna end well.
饿吗？
Hungry?
救命
Help!
来人啊 救命啊
Please, somebody help us!
救命
Help!
来人啊 别碰…
Please! Don't...
别乱动
Stay still.
你想我们怎么样？
What do you want with us?
那段录音…
That voice...
提到了我们可以
It said salvation
得到救赎
can be ours if we,
只要我们洗心革面 因说谎而忏悔
cleanse our soul of our lies.
这算是个狗屁告解室吗？
This is some kind of fucked up confessional?
真实的话语会让我们自由
The truth will set us free.
亲爱的 我的灵魂很干净
Honey, my soul is clean.
我叫安娜
It's Anna.
而你刚才说的都是屁话
And, bullshit.
我叫米奇
I'm Mitch.
你叫什么
What's your name?
卡莉
Carly.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
这是哪个变态开的混账玩笑？
This is some bastard's sick idea of a joke?
他说这是个游戏
He said it was a game.
对我们来说 要真是游戏就好了
Well, then I hope, for all of our sakes, that it is a game.
是吗？为什么这么说 甜心？
Oh, yeah? Why's that, sweetheart?
因为游戏是可以赢的
Because games can be won.
这可真疯狂
This is cray
怎么回事？
What the hell?
- 有人报警了吗？- 是的
- Did anyone phone the police? - Yeah.
下手投掷
Underhand!
过肩投掷
Overhand!
好啊 你状态不错啊
Okay, you got some heat on it!
我关机是有原因的 哈洛伦
Cell phone's off for a reason, halloran.
埃尔 你怎么看？
Well, what do you think, El?
我不知道 他看上去有点苍白
I don't know, he looks a little pale.
把这东西拿下来
Let's get this thing off.
有人在效仿约翰·克莱默
Someone's been studying up on John Kramer.
是个模仿型罪犯？
A copycat?
最好不是 克莱默都死了10年了
Hope not. Kramer's been dead for 10 years.
- 基思 - 你好吗 医生？
- Keith! - What's up, doc?
- 嘿 哥们 你还好吗？- 我很好
- Hey, man, how you doing? - I'm good.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Good to see you. - You too, man.
你现在来这儿工作了吗？
You're, uh... You're working this neighborhood now?
是啊 上个月我刚调到凶杀科
Uh, yeah, I joined homicide last month.
老天爷啊 这家伙经历了什么？
Jesus, what happened to this guy?
你们俩认识？
You two know each other?
洛根是我们在费卢杰的医生
Logan was our medic in fallujah.
嘿 我对克里斯汀的遭遇深感遗憾
Hey, uh, I'm sorry to hear about Christine.
你还好吧 伙计？
How you been, man?
还好 基思
Uh, good, Keith.
对 我调整得很好
Yeah, I'm doing well.
好吧
All right.
埃莉诺
Eleanor.
这是什么？
What is it?
切开看看吧
Okay, then.
"还有四个"
"And then there were four..."
你这有电脑能插这U盘吗？
You got a computer we could stick that in?
游戏又开始了
The games have begun again.
一旦开始就不会结束
And they will not stop
直到赎完所有的罪过
until the sins against the innocent are atoned for.
接下来的四个目标由我来负责
I will take care of the next four,
其余的都归你管了
you take care of the rest.
我们得把这录音拿去做声音识别
We gotta get that to voice rec.
这声音不是他
It's not him.
不可能是他的
It can't be.
对吗？
Right?
该死
Oh, shit.
(忏悔)
这他妈是什么？
What the fuck?
这他妈是什么情况？
这一点都不吓人
No, that's not creepy at all.
不 不
No. No!
不 不 不…
No, no, no...
救命
Help!
谁来救救我们
Somebody please help us!
这个变态要把我们拉到哪去？
Where is this sick fuck taking us?
你们有看到过什么吗？
Did anyone see anything?
什么也没看到 我他妈被人下药了
No, nothing. I got fucking drugged!
他说"忏悔"
He said, "confess."
我们必须忏悔
We have to confess.
是吗 你有什么想忏悔的吗？
Yeah, you got something you want to confess?
开始啊 说啊
Have at it. Come on!
该死的 我们都有要忏悔的事
Damn it, we all have something to confess.
我曾经卖了一辆摩托车给一个小孩
I sold a kid a bike once.
他买走摩托 10分钟后他就出事故了
He had an accident 10 minutes after I sold it to him.
他驾驭不了马力这么强的摩托
It's not my fault he couldn't handle
可这不是我的错 对吧
such a powerful damn bike, all right?
- 他死了 - 就这样？
- He died! - That's it?
你只干了这事？你卖了辆摩托 那小孩出车祸死了？
That's all you did? You sold a kid a bike he died on?
- 行了 伙计 - 就这事 没别的了
- Come on, man! - That's it! I said that's it, man!
你别扯淡了 那你呢 亲爱的？
Yeah, bullshit. And what about you, sweetheart?
说吧
Come on.
我们的孩子死了
We lost our baby.
安娜…安娜
Anna... Anna.
告诉我这都不是真的
Tell me that this isn't happening.
我丈夫犯了个错
My husband made a mistake.
不 不 不 这算不上什么忏悔 继续 快点
No, no, no. That's not a confession, come on. Come on!
- 说啊 - 我不知道你他妈的想让我说什么 好吗？
- Come on! - I don't know what the fuck you want me to say, okay?
- 是我导致我们的婚姻破碎 - 不 不
- I let our marriage fall apart. - No, no.
"我在塔尔萨杀了一个妓女"这才算是忏悔
A confession is, "i killed a hooker in Tulsa",
或者"我他妈吃了我邻居"
or, "i ate my fucking neighbor."
不是"我需要婚姻咨询"
Not, "i need marriage counseling."
- 卡莉 你呢？- 没有
- Carly? - No.
- 我什么都想不起来 - 好吧 那快点想
- Nothing I can think of. - Yeah, well, think faster!
还是你自己快点想吧
You think faster!
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
我们要被吊死了
We're going to hang.
快点放那个录音带 米奇
Play the damn tape, Mitch.
天啊
Oh, god!
(播放我)
我知道你们都想
While I am certain that there is
因为之前的血之献祭
a desire to point fingers at me
而来指责我
for the blood that has been shed,
但除非你们先指责自己
unless you turn that finger inward,
否则我保证你们会流更多的血
I assure you, more blood will be lost
而且所有人都面临审判
and all will be judged.
我们先从你们其中之一开始
We will begin with one.
这位不只是个骗子
One who is not only a liar,
- 还是个贼 - 嘿
- but a thief. - Hey!
一个抢包的贼
A purse-snatcher.
但当你有机会
And when you had a chance
去弥补你造成的伤害时
to fix the harm that you'd done,
你却选择袖手旁观
you chose to do nothing.
现在你可能会因为没有得到有效的治疗而死去
Now it is you who could die without the right medication.
在你们都处于昏迷状态时 你们当中的这个骗子
While unconscious, this deceiver among you,
这个罪人被注射了毒药
this criminal, was injected with a poison.
你们面前的这几个注射器中
One of the syringes in front of you
有一个装着解药
holds the antidote.
一个装着盐水
One is a saline solution,
另一个注射器里装的都是令人死状极惨的酸
the other, an acid that will cause an excruciating death.
如果注射了正确的药 你们的锁链都将被解开
Inject the correct one and your chains will be released.
如果没有选对药
Failure to make the right choice
会导致你们全体死亡
could result in death for you all.
我问你们 对你们来说 一条命值多少钱？
I ask you, what is a life worth to you?
是谁 赶紧坦白吧 要不我们都得死
One of you 'fess up, or we all die.
- 好吧 检查自己身上是不是有痕迹 - 什么？
- Okay, check yourself for marks. - Huh?
如果他给我们注射了 会留下痕迹
If he injected us, there could be marks.
就是你了
Bingo.
- 你在干什么？- 没事的 没事的
- What are you doing? - It's okay, it's okay.
你只需要选一个注射器 美女
You just got to pick a needle, blondie.
听着 只要你选对了解药 我们就能拿掉这些东西
Look, we get out of these things when you pick an antidote.
不然我们都会死 卡莉
Or else we all die, Carly!
不 不 万一是酸呢？
No, no. What if it's the acid?
- 我不选 - 你不选个屁啊
- I won't. - Bullshit, you won't.
或许只需你忏悔呢 卡莉
Maybe just confess, Carly.
对吧 你是偷包的贼吗？
Okay, did you steal purses?
是 几年前了 但是我没杀死任何人啊
Yeah, years ago, but I didn't kill anyone!
不 不 这可不是那家伙想要的
No, no, no! No, that's not the repentant attitude
忏悔的态度 好吗
this guy's looking for, okay?
你撒谎 你撒谎
You're lying. You're lying!
不 我当时身无分文 好吗？没错
No! I was broke, okay? And yes,
是有人死了 但那不是我的错
somebody died, but it wasn't my fault.
好吧
Okay.
- 赶紧选 否则我把这三支都扎到你身上 - 不
- Choose, or I'm gonna stick them all into you! - No!
- 哥们 冷静 - 你是在开玩笑吗？住手
- Yo, man! - Are you kidding me? Stop!
先让她看看
Just let her look!
这些数字哪个对你来说有实际意义
Do any of these numbers mean anything to you?
- 现在就选 - 我在努力
- Choose now! - I'm trying!
3.53美元
$3.53.
什么？这数字什么意思？
What? What does that mean?
- 什么？- 一条命对我来说值多少
- What? - What a life is worth to me.
我操
Oh, fuck...
现在就选 来啊 选一支
Choose, right now! Come on, pick!
- 选一支 现在就选 - 求你了 我真选不出
- Pick one! Pick now! - Please! I can't do it.
- 赶紧选一支啊 - 要不我们都会死的
- Pick one now! - We're all going to die!
- 快选 - 快点
- Pick now! - Come on.
- 快选 - 快啊 卡莉 选一支
- Choose! - Come on, pick one, Carly!
我他妈选不出来
I'm not gonna fucking do it!
不 我才不选
No, I'm not going to!
- 去你妈的 我不选 - 赶紧选啊
- Fuck you! I won't do it. - Pick one, now!
快点 快选 选
Come on, pick! Pick!
该死 我不选
Fuck! I'm not gonna pick!
快选 卡莉 现在就选
Now! Now, Carly, now!
现在就选
Pick now!
选一支
Pick one!
- 你这混蛋 - 嘿 嘿
- Fucking asshole! - Hey! Hey!
又不是我害大家到这里的
I'm not the one who put us here.
控制一下你自己
Get a hold of yourself.
我刚救了大家的命
I just saved our lives.
是啊 但是你夺走了她的命 你杀了她
Yeah, but you took hers! You killed her.
- 你个自私的混账 - 不 住手
- You selfish son of a bitch. - No, stop!
你们两个都冷静一下
Both of y'all need to chill!
你他妈怎么回事？
What the hell?
一条命值3.53美元
A life is worth $3.53.
- 什么？- 她就是那么说的
- What? - That's what she said.
是的
Yeah.
3.53美元
$3.53.
注射器内还有其他数字
There's more numbers on the inside of this.
有可能是组合
It could be the combination.
齿痕鉴定确认了铁桶头的身份是马尔科姆·尼尔
Dental ids buckethead as Malcolm neale.
马尔科姆·尼尔？我记得那个案子
Malcolm neale? I remember that case.
他的老婆五年前遭人谋杀
His wife was murdered five years ago.
入室行凶 直接切开了喉咙
A home invasion. Perp slit her throat.
- 罪犯还让他在旁边看着 - 对 对
- They made him watch. - Oh, yeah, yeah.
我想起来了 马尔科姆·尼尔是个堕落的赌徒
I remember. Malcolm neale was a, uh, degenerate gambler.
他妻子的死其实该怪罪于他 他欠了别人的钱
Wife's murder was on him. He owed some bad guys some money.
那你们有没有给这些坏人定罪？
And did you ever get around to convicting those bad guys?
指甲的抓痕
Scratch marks from fingernails.
看来他有过一番挣扎 可能是跟杀他的嫌疑犯
There was a struggle, presumably with the killer.
头被砍了一部分
The partial decapitation
是由电圆锯造成的
was made by a circular saw.
伤口处发现氧化铁
There are traces of ferric oxide,
赤铁矿的痕迹
hematite, in the wound.
- 电圆锯刃口生锈 - 好的
- Rust, from blades. - Okay.
录音查的怎么样了？
What about the voice recording?
U盘上查到什么了吗？
Anything off the flash drive?
录音确实与约翰·克莱默的声音相吻合
The voice was John Kramer. Matched.
- 完全吻合 - 吻合？
- Identical. - Matched?
什么意思 他起死回生了？
What, he came back from the dead?
又不是第一次
Wouldn't be his first time.
就算人死了
Just because someone is dead
不代表没人能弄到他的声音
doesn't mean they can't have a voice.
给我们足够的时间 我们就能替死人说话
Give us enough time, we speak for the dead.
在楼顶时 埃德加·曼森好像说了什么游戏已经开始了
On the roof, Edgar munsen was spouting off about starting a game.
录音里说还有4名潜在的受害人
The recording says there are four more potential victims.
四个人在为生存而努力
Four people fighting for their lives.
天啊…
God...
好吧 我们应该在乡下某个地方
Okay, we're in the countryside somewhere.
我看不到任何标志性的建筑 什么都没有
I can't make out any landmarks, nothing.
天啊
Oh, god.
谁在对我们做这样的事？
Who's doing this to us?
我不知道
I have no idea.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
瑞安
Ryan.
那你又有什么罪呢 瑞安？
And what's your sin, Ryan?
倒卖不良抵押资产 出售高质量毒品
Sold bad mortgages, sold good coke,
逃税 出轨
cheated on my taxes, cheated on my wife.
家和国我都骗了 所以 你看…
Both of them. So, you know...
还没那么坏
Nothing that bad.
你的故事是什么 棒棒糖？
What's your story, lollipop?
都是我丈夫的错
It was my husband's fault.
行了吧 别扯淡了
Oh, come on. Bullshit.
为什么…为什么我要因为他犯的错受惩罚？
Why... why am I being punished for something that he did?
为什么啊？
Huh?
如果他没有睡着
If he hadn't fallen asleep,
他就不会翻身
he wouldn't have rolled over
也不会把我们的孩子闷死
and suffocated our baby.
这不是我的错
It's not my fault.
不 不 不要
No, no. No!
说真的 你不觉得他是想告诉我们什么吗？
For real, you don't think he's trying to tell us something?
(没有出口)
看 那儿有两扇完好的门
Look, there are two perfectly good doors right here.
对 然后走进门后就到了他想让我们去的地方？
Right, so we'll go through the door that leads exactly he wants us to go?
- 不 谢谢 - 不 米奇说的对
- No, thanks. - No, Mitch is right.
- 我不认为这是个… - 给老子退后
- I don't think this is... - Back the fuck up.
别他妈用这玩意指着我
Man, get that shit out of my face.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my god!
帮帮我 帮我 求求你
Help me! Help. Please.
这他妈是怎么了？
Ah! What the fuck?
那有线 还有些别的东西…
There's wires, there's something...
帮帮我 帮帮我
Help, help.
安娜 你看见了吗？
Anna? Do you see?
他腿上缠着100多根电线 还有一些滑轮
There's 100 wires wrapped around his leg, and around some pulleys.
好吧 有..有某种把手
Okay, there's, uh... There's some kind of handle.
伙计们 有卷磁带
Guys, there's a tape.
更紧了 越来越紧了
It's tighter! It just got tighter!
- 我的天啊 - 好吧…
- Oh, god! - Okay...
天啊
God! Oh!
我们怎么才能拿到磁带？
Okay, how do we get the tape?
- 慢慢来 - 好 小心点
- Hey, go slow. - Yeah, careful.
- 一定要慢 - 好的
- Really slow. - Okay, okay.
小心 小心
Careful. Careful.
拜托了 小心点
Please, be careful.
天啊
Oh, god.
小心 小心 小心
Careful, careful, careful.
天啊
Oh, god!
天啊 我的天啊
Oh, god! Oh, my god!
你们俩什么忙都帮不上
You guys aren't helping!
去拿磁带 去拿磁带
Grab the tape! Grab the tape!
不行啊
No way, man.
不 你得去拿那破磁带
No, you gotta fucking grab the tape.
我救了你的命 米奇 去拿磁带
I saved your fucking life, Mitch! Grab the tape!
- 快去拿 - 求你了
- Just do it! - Please.
求你了 对 对 加油
Please, yeah. Yeah, come on.
加油 加油 伙计
Come on. Come on, man.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
你快拿到了吧？
You almost got it?
- 我在努力呢 老兄 - 你可以的 可以的
- I'm trying, dude. - You got it, you got it.
好的 好的 你拿到了吗？
All good, all good. You got it?
天啊 太好了
Oh, god, oh, good.
你拿到了吗？
You got it?
播放吧 米奇 播放吧
Play the tape, Mitch. Play the tape.
给 你来播放吧
Here, you play the tape, man.
生活没有捷径
There are no shortcuts in life.
请原谅我相对残忍的示例
Please forgive the rather crude example
我会给你们选择是否要遵从规矩的自由
I will make of your decision to not follow the rules.
拉下把手你们就自由了
Pull the handle and you will be set free.
他说"自由了"是什么意思？
What does he mean "set free"?
祝你好运 棒棒糖
Good luck, lollipop.
天啊
Oh, god.
嘿
Hey,
铁桶头的初步验尸报告出来了
prelim report on buckethead.
说是在尸体上发现的微粒是动物粪便
It says the particles found on the body are animal feces.
牛 鸡还有猪的
Cow, chicken, pig.
他们还发现了奥耶斯基病毒的痕迹
They also found traces of aujeszky's disease.
- 奥耶斯基病毒？- 是一种病毒
- Aujeszky's disease? - It's a virus.
为人所熟知是因为
Mostly known because,
如果猪感染了 农场主就得灭掉整个猪群
when swine get it, farmers have to wipe out the entire sounder.
出乎意料
I'm impressed.
继续查吧
Keep digging.
- 或许我能根据病毒查到某个地点 - 尼尔森医生
- Maybe I can track the virus to a location. - Dr. Nelson?
又一名死者 可能是跳楼的
Another one, possible jumper.
死者身上有什么身份证明吗？
Any identification on the victim?
没有 似乎是同一个凶手所为
No. Looks like the same killer.
这是在尸体上找到的
This was on the body.
(还剩三个...)
目前还跟我们的嫌疑人都没有什么关系
No link so far to any of our suspects.
这是克雷默吗 你们知道吗
Is it Kramer? Do you know?
这件案子与竖锯有关吗？
Is this crime related to Jigsaw?
这件案子发生在埃德加·曼森所住的医院是巧合吗？
Think it's any coincidence that Edgar munsen happens to be a guest here?
我觉得他不太可能从昏迷中苏醒过来
I think it's highly unlikely he woke up from a coma,
然后爬到屋顶 把这个女孩扔了下来
climbed on a roof, and threw a girl off.
但我确实跟重症监护室联系过了 他还在那里
But I did check with the icu. He's still there.
像是某种酸
Looks like acid.
尸体肌肉纤维中三磷酸腺苷消损殆尽
There's a depletion of adenosine triphosphate in the muscles fibers.
所以才会尸僵
Rigor mortis.
显然 她不是摔死的
Clearly, she didn't die from the fall.
是氢氟酸
It's hydrofluoric acid.
看这里 有一处注射针孔
Look, here. This is the injection point.
通过血管一路抵达心脏 然后燃烧了
The vein carried it all the way to the heart, where it's singed.
你怎么知道是氢氟酸的？
How do you know it was hydrofluoric acid?
在费卢杰看到过很多
Saw a lot of it in fallujah.
但从没见过注射的
Never injected, though.
一个拼图碎片
A puzzle piece.
他妈的竖锯
Jig-fucking-saw!
洛根是怎么回事？在费卢杰城到底发生了什么？
What's Logan's deal? What happened in fallujah?
呃 他…
Uh, he, uh...
他被俘虏了
He got captured. Oh.
但是 是在击毙了三名塔利班成员之后
Um, but not before taking out three Taliban.
我听说 敌人对他严刑拷打
Uh, what I heard, they tortured the shit out of him.
他回来后在退伍军人医院呆了好几个月
He spent months in the va hospital when he got back.
你觉得他还正常吗？
You think he snapped?
拜托伙计 你说的可是我的一个兄弟啊
Come on, man, you're talking about a brother, here.
我也有个兄弟 他就是个混蛋
I got a brother. He's a fucking asshole.
你怎么看他的助手 埃莉诺
What do you think about his second, Eleanor?
她屁股很翘 嘴太大了
She's got a great ass, big mouth.
- 似乎对这变态事件感到很兴奋 - 是啊
- Seems to get off on this sick shit. - Yeah.
妈的王八蛋
Motherfucker!
该死 又他妈怎么了？
Shit. What the fuck?
我操
Oh, fuck.
我是个好人
I'm a good person.
我是个好人 别这样对我
I'm a good person, i don't deserve this.
我忏悔…
I confess...
我忏悔 我忏…
I confess. I con...
我忏悔 这事太他妈操蛋了
I confess that this is fucked up!
那是什么？
What?
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
Hey, guys!
有人打开了电视
Somebody turned on the TV.
(按播放键)
有人吗？
Hello?
我们这也有一台电视
Yeah, we got one, too.
- 我得把你举起来 - 什么？
- I'm going to have to lift you. - What?
我们得拿到遥控器
We gotta get the remote.
(按播放键)
好吧
Okay, fine.
拿到了吗？
Got it?
拿到了
Got it!
不 不
No! No!
不
No!
过去你们经常损人利己
In the past, you have all put your own interests above others,
然后欺骗自己
and then lied to yourselves,
对世界隐瞒你们的麻木不仁 你们的偷盗行为
and deceived the world about your callousness, your larceny,
和你们犯下的各种罪行
your criminality.
现在 你们要对着镜子
Now, you will look in the mirror
面对你们的真实面目
and you will face who you really are.
你们所做的选择可能会害你们丢掉性命
The choices you have made may cost you your life.
你们不能逃避事实
You cannot escape the truth.
然而 有一人可以帮你们
There is, however, one person who can help you.
瑞安
Ryan.
如果他在你们被活埋之前拉动操作杆
If he pulls the lever before you are buried alive,
你们就能活
you will live.
瑞安 解放自己 才能解救他们
Ryan, free yourself to free them.
瑞安
Ryan.
瑞安？
Ryan?
不 不
No! No!
那是什么？
What is that?
是谷物
It's grain!
瑞安 我们要被活埋了
Ryan, man, we're going to get buried alive.
瑞安
Ryan!
快去拉操作杆 瑞安
Get to the handle! Ryan!
我做不到
I can't!
- 瑞安 - 求你了 瑞安
- Ryan! - Please, Ryan!
快点啊
Hurry, man!
瑞安
Ryan!
你必须这样做
You have to do it!
快去拉操作杆
Get to the handle!
瑞安 快他妈拉操作杆
Ryan, pull the fucking handle!
求你了
Please!
你有什么故事 亲爱的？
What's your story, sweetheart?
你想问我什么 警探？
What are you asking, detective?
你就是那种喜欢重口味的 是吧？
You one of those, uh, kinky types?
- 喜欢疼痛的感觉？- 为什么这么说？
- Like a little pain? - Why?
你想被惩罚吗？
You want to get punished?
太晚了
Too late.
我已经有个天天折磨我的前妻了
Already got an ex-wife that tortures me every day.
- 也许你活该 - 大概是吧
- Maybe you deserve it. - Probably.
马尔科姆·尼尔被杀那晚你在哪？
Where were you the night Malcolm neale got murdered?
家里
Home.
- 独自一人 - 好的
- Alone. - Cool.
对了 你能证明吗？
Oh. Can you prove that?
我需要证明吗？
Do I need to?
- 早点回家来 爸爸 - 我会的
- Come home soon, daddy. - I will.
很抱歉又让你等到这么晚 朱迪
I'm sorry you have to stay so late again, Judy.
这你就别操心啦
Don't worry about it.
好吧 睡个好觉 梅尔 我爱你
All right, sleep sweet, Mel. I love you.
- 我也爱你老爸 - 爱你 拜拜
- Love you too, daddy. - Love you, bye.
拜拜
Bye.
洛根
Logan.
你在哪找到埃莉诺的？
How did you find Eleanor?
我那个助手？
My assistant?
她只是你的助手吗？
Is that all she is?
克里斯汀过世两年了 真的是…
It's been two years since Christine passed. It's just...
我不会怪你的
I wouldn't blame you.
是的 但是我是专业的
Yes, but I'm a professional.
洛根 你有没有听说过
Uh, Logan, you ever heard
一个叫"竖锯游戏规则"的网站？
of a website called "Jigsaw rules"?
- 没有 - 在网络里藏的很深
- No. - Buried deep online.
做了些调查 但这是个致力于竖锯游戏的网站
Took some digging, but it's a site devoted to Jigsaw.
一半的内容都是些装腔作势的人在胡扯
Half of it's bullshit, posers,
但是网站里确实有不少令人不安的东西
but there's some stuff on there that is really messed up.
- 网站上有很多变态 - 那又怎么样呢？
- A lot of sick fucks. - Okay?
我们做了暗网IP地址排查
We did a darknet ip trawl.
你的助手没少光顾这个网站
Got a lot of hits from your assistant.
她是网站的常客
She's a regular.
下载了很多你无法想象的东西
Downloaded some shit you cannot imagine.
所以 你是说埃莉诺·邦尼维尔就是我们要找的模仿犯？
So you're saying that Eleanor bonneville is our copycat?
不 我们不是这个意思
No, that's not what we're saying.
你查过她的不在场证明了吗？
Did you check her alibi?
她说铁桶男尸被发现
Uh, she said she was home
吊在公园里的那天早上 她在家里
the morning that buckethead was found hanging in the park.
早上七点？独自在家？单身女性？
At 7:00 A.M.? Home alone? A single woman?
- 确实有点可疑 - 好的 那我们回到刚才的问题
- That does sound suspicious. - All right, let's rewind.
埃莉诺是怎么找上你的？
How did Eleanor come to you?
她找到这个部门来完成实习
She sought out the department to do her residency.
之后呢？
And after that?
她实习结束后呢？
After she finished her residency?
我是说 三个月前 有份工作想签她
I mean, three months ago, she was offered a job
去克利夫兰市太平间从事尸检工作
running the show at the Cleveland city morgue.
为什么她没选择去那工作？
Why didn't she take that?
你会想搬到克利夫兰吗？
Would you want to move to Cleveland?
实验室来的电话 结果出来了
That's the lab. Results are in.
这个是在受害人马尔科姆·尼尔
Okay, so this is the DNA of the blood
指甲内血迹里的DNA
scraped from under the fingernails of the first victim, Malcolm neale.
对 铁桶男尸 能确认身份了吗？
Yeah, buckethead. Can you ID it?
已经确认了
Already did.
这是十年前一个罪犯的血液样本
This is a blood sample from a perp taken a decade ago.
你应该还记得那个案子
You might remember the case.
完全吻合
It's an exact match.
是谁的血？
Whose blood is it?
约翰·克莱默的
John Kramer.
什么？
What?
这不可能
That's impossible.
这是事实
That's a fact.
我们第一个受害人指甲里的血
The blood under the fingernails of our first victim
是约翰·克莱默的血？
is John Kramer's blood.
那个竖锯杀人狂
The Jigsaw killer.
瑞安
Ryan!
救命
Help!
- 瑞安 - 救命啊
- Ryan! - Help!
快去拉操作杆
Pull the lever!
瑞安
Ryan!
快去拉操作杆
Get to the handle!
瑞安
Ryan!
救命啊
Help, now!
瑞安
Ryan!
不
No!
去死吧
Go to hell!
你得帮帮我们
You gotta help us out, man!
救命啊
Help!
该死 该死
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
瑞安
Ryan!
- 去拉操作杆 瑞安 - 瑞安
- Pull the handle, Ryan! - Ryan!
去拉啊
Pull it!
瑞安
Ryan!
我们快死在这了 求你了
We're gonna die in here! Please!
看着上帝的份上 快拉啊
For the love of god, just pull it!
如果我们死了 你也活不了
If we die, you die!
上帝啊…
God...
快关上 上帝啊
Turn it off. Oh, god...
这是博纳维尔女士手机的GPS定位
Here's the GPS location on Ms. bonneville's cell.
好极了
Great.
竖锯死了吗？
Is Jigsaw dead?
克莱默死了吗 我们有证据吗
Did Kramer die, or do we have proof?
你要对所有惊慌失措的市民说些什么？
What do you have to say to all the panicked citizens
谁想要答案？
who want answers?
(啤酒月酒吧餐厅)
你关机了？
Turned your phone off?
可你还是来了 你找到了我
And yet here you are, you found me.
你当警探的话会很出色的
You'd make a good detective.
也许是我这个人太容易被猜透了
Or maybe I'm just too predictable.
猜透？不
Predictable? No.
哈洛伦起疑心了
Halloran's passing the blame around.
他盯上我们俩了
He's looking at us.
是的
Yeah.
他们派人监视我家
They're watching my house.
因为他觉得你的不在场证明是胡扯
Because he thinks your alibi is shit.
你好像挺喜欢那家伙的啊？
You really love that guy, huh?
在郡里工作的第一年 一个很简单的案子
First year at county, clean case,
一个叫阿利斯泰尔·舒尔茨的罪犯
a predator by the name of alistair Schultz.
在被拘留的时候 哈洛伦把他给揍了
Halloran roughed him up while he was in custody
律师利用了这一点帮他脱罪
and the lawyer used that to get him off.
放出来的第二天 他就杀了一个8岁的女孩
The very next day, he kills an 8-year-old girl
那女孩的尸检是我做的
who shows up on my table.
她是第一个受害者
The first of many.
哈洛伦自控能力很差
Halloran can't help himself,
总是控制不住自己
can't get out of his own way.
所以 不 我并不喜欢那个家伙
So, no, I don't have much love for the guy.
但这是工作 洛根
Well, it's a job, Logan.
你不能夹杂私人感情
You can't make it personal.
等你也有个小女儿时…
When you have a little girl one day...
你为什么不告诉我克利夫兰那份工作的事情？
Why didn't you tell me about the job offer in Cleveland?
- 因为你肯定会让我接受 - 没错
- Because you would have told me to take it. - Yes.
- 没错 我当然会让你接受 - 这很复杂
- Yes, you're damn right i would. - It's complicated.
再复杂的事情我们都经历过
We are past complicated.
铁桶头死的那晚
When buckethead was strung up,
我并不在家 我对警察撒谎了
I wasn't at home like I told the cops.
我在自己的…
I was at my, uh...
工作室
Studio.
什么工作室？
What studio?
- 为什么你不和他们说实话？- 正如我说的
- And why couldn't you tell them that? - Like I said,
这…这件事很复杂
it's... it's complicated.
你认为他们会查不出来吗？
You don't think they're going to find out about it?
他们知道竖锯的粉丝网站
They know about the Jigsaw fan website,
不管你们他妈的在上面干什么
whatever the fuck you're doing on that.
他们都会一清二楚
They're going to find out about everything.
埃莉诺 他们认为我也参与其中
El, they think I'm involved.
带我去看看吧
Show me.
天啊 我应该提醒你 因为…
Oh, Jesus! Okay, I should warn you, because...
你能把灯打开吗？
Can you turn the lights on?
埃莉诺
Eleanor,
这是什么？
what is this?
嘿 女孩也得有自己的爱好啊
Hey, a girl's gotta have a hobby.
爱好？你管这个叫爱好？
A hobby? Is that what you call it?
你怎么不去集邮？那才叫爱好
How about a stamp collection? That's a hobby.
很漂亮 不是吗？
It's beautiful, isn't it?
据说 这个机关是约翰·克莱默
Supposedly, John Kramer designed this trap
在其他那些人之前设计的一个游戏
for a game that took place before all the others.
他们在他的实验室里发现了设计稿
They found the plans in his lab.
我亲手做的
I built it myself.
我从是网上的某些家伙那儿弄到的设计稿
Got them from some guy on the Internet.
传言说 约翰不仅仅设计了它
Rumor is, not only did John design this,
他还造了一个实物
he built one.
抱歉 要让你失望了
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint,
但是克莱默的受害者中 没有人死于这样的机关
but none of Kramer's victims died in any device like this.
伤口和这个机关都不相符
The wounds don't match the design.
可能是尸体一直还没被发现
Well, maybe the bodies were never found.
也可能这个游戏从未进行过
And maybe it never happened.
可能是有人在耍你
Maybe someone's playing games with you.
你搞这些东西干什么？
What are you doing with all this stuff?
你现在得放弃这种爱好了
You need to get rid of it, now.
干得漂亮 现在我们有正当的理由了
Great work. Now we've got probable cause.
- 你绝对不会相信的 - 什么？
- You're not going to believe this. - What?
特派员想看看竖锯的遗体
The commissioner wants to see Jigsaw's remains.
想证明他真的死了
Wants proof he's really dead.
- 什么？- 是的
- What? - Yeah.
- 他说想平息民众的恐惧 - 你认真的吗？
- Said he wants to calm the peoples' fears. - Are you serious?
追查一个死人
Chasing a dead man.
这都是选举年的狗屁
This is election year bullshit.
这件事交给你了 我还要处理这些
That is all yours. I'm going to follow up on these.
好的
Right on.
(美国退伍军人事务部 洛根·尼尔森中尉)
(洛根·尼尔森副队 1973年8月18日出生  男性  白种人  1.88米  176斤)
(医疗巡逻队...  严刑拷打...)
(伤情复发...)
哈洛伦
Halloran.
他在昏迷中 怎么可能会消失？
He's in a fucking coma, how does he just disappear?
他还有呼吸
He's still breathing.
那是什么？
What is it?
上面有我的名字
It says my name.
你知道 如果我们违反规则会发生什么
You know what happens if we don't follow the rules.
你好 米奇
Hello, Mitch.
你已经承认你曾把一辆摩托车卖给一个男孩
You've admitted to selling a boy a motorcycle.
但你并没有说出全部实情 对吗？
But you have not told the entire story, have you?
你给这辆600美元的摩托车 列了一张漂亮的性能表
$600 for a bike that you listed in excellent condition.
即使你明知刹车是坏的
Even though you knew the brakes were faulty.
你拿了他的600美元
You took his 600 bucks
做为回报 你将他推向了死路
and, in return, you delivered him to his end.
他是我的侄子 他从来没伤害过任何人
He was my nephew, and he never hurt anyone.
你眼前的这个装置有个特殊的电源
The device you see here has a unique power source.
和你卖给我侄子的那辆摩托车的引擎一样
It's the same engine that graced the bike you sold my nephew.
我操
Fuck.
但是 我向你保证
However, I assure you,
这个刹车装置运行地很完美
the brake lever for this one works perfectly.
- 该死 - 听着 你说的都对 伙计
- Oh shit. - Look, you're right, man!
避开你周围的危险
Avoid the dangers around you,
拉下操作杆 摩托车就能停下来
hit the motorcycle brake handle and the motor will stop.
- 我操 - 是生还是死 米奇
- Oh, shit. - Live or die, Mitch.
由你来选择
The choice is yours.
该死 不 不 不
Shit! No, no, no!
我操
Oh, shit.
听着 我错了 快停下 拜托
Look, I'm sorry! Stop, please!
对你侄子的事情我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your nephew!
安娜 救命
Anna, help!
快他妈的上来
Get the fuck up here!
我不想死
I don't want to die!
停下 快停下
Stop! Stop it!
停下
Stop!
安娜 你得救救我
Anna, you got to help me!
快点 快啊 拜托
Hurry up! Hurry, please!
拜托救救我 快点 快点
Please help! Hurry! Hurry!
我不想死 我不想死
I don't want to die! I don't want to die!
米奇 拉那个操作杆
Mitch, pull the brake!
拉那个操作杆
Pull the brake!
天啊
Oh... oh, god.
安娜 你做到了
Anna, you did it!
你救了我
You saved me!
安娜…安娜 求你快我救出去
Anna... Anna, get me out of here, please.
你做到了
You did it!
Man, you did it!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
埃德加·曼森当时昏迷不醒
Edgar Munsen was in a coma.
你就这么一件事
You got one job!
只有这一件事要做 你个没用的混…
One job to do, you useless mother...
喂
Yeah.
(约翰·克莱默)
有什么线索吗？
Anything?
没有
Nothing.
像变戏法一样就这么没了 没人看见
Pulled a Houdini. Nobody saw shit.
正在把克莱默的棺材拉出来
Just pulling Kramer's casket out now.
有记者吗？
Reporters?
有
Yup.
很好
Good.
彻底结束这些流言吧
End this nonsense once and for all.
约翰·克莱默已经死了十年了
John Kramer is dead and has been for 10 years.
结束这场闹剧吧
Enough of this John Kramer bullshit.
你可能得重新考虑下
You may want to rethink that.
怎么了？发生什么了？
Why? What's going on?
这样说吧 你可以停止对埃德加·曼森的追捕了
Let's just say you can call off the hunt for Edgar Munsen.
不是吧
Oh, come on!
好了 申请逮捕博纳维尔 我们在那见
Okay, get a warrant for Bonneville, I'll see you there.
- 上 上 上 - 冲 冲 冲
- Go, go, go. - Move, move, move. Go!
我们上
Let's go.
你去左边 右边去两个
Take the left, two on the right.
上 上 上 上 上
Go, go, go, go, go!
- 左边安全 - 安全
- Clear on the left! - Clear!
- 注意左边 - 抬头
- Watch your left. - Eyes up.
你进去了吗？
You in?
(竖锯身份揭晓 警方将在新闻发布会上公布其姓名)
(竖锯再度出手 连环杀人案 警方扔没找到任何嫌疑人)
上帝啊
Jesus!
(还剩两个...)
还剩两个存活
Two left.
所以呢 博纳维尔就这么把一具尸体
So, what, Bonneville just leaves a body
挂在她的工作室里？
hanging in her studio?
- 不是吧 伙计 - 我知道
- Come on, man. - I know.
我去找洛根
I'm gonna go pick up Logan.
我去找那个女孩
I'll get the girl.
我需要你把手伸出来 兄弟
I'm gonna need you to show me those wrists, brother.
- 我什么也没做 基思 - 听着 听着
- I didn't do anything, Keith. - Look, listen, listen.
我有你的照片
I have photos of you.
没错 就是你和埃莉诺 在那间满是刑具的仓库里
Yeah, you and Eleanor in your warehouse of torture devices.
- 等等 你当时也在？- 是的 我也在
- Wait, you were there? - Yeah, I was there.
我看到第三具尸体 像是掉进了绞肉机里一样
I just saw a third body that looks like it's been through a meat grinder.
是有人想陷害我们 好吗？
All right. Someone is trying to frame us. All right?
- 你得告诉我埃莉诺在哪儿 - 工作室的事我可以解释
- I want you to tell me where Eleanor is. - The studio I can explain.
- 你得相信… - 你知不知道她在哪？
- You just have to trust... - Do you know where she is or not?
基思 我会把我知道的都告诉你
Keith, I'll tell you everything I know.
我知道是谁干的
I know who did this.
你也知道
And you do, too.
是谁发现埃莉诺工作室里的尸体的？
Who found the body at Eleanor's studio?
天啊
Jesus!
- 哈洛伦 - 他有动机
- Halloran. - He had motive.
他想让埃德加死
He wanted Edgar dead.
是谁下令瞄准遥控器的？
Who ordered the targeting of the remote?
如果他有任何危险举动 就打爆它
If he moves to trigger it, blow it to shit.
继续说
Go on.
所有人都在瞄准遥控器
Yeah, everybody targeted the trigger,
但有没有人看到
but did anyone actually see
哈洛伦瞄准的是哪里吗？
what halloran was aiming at?
他根本没打算让埃德加活着
He had no plan to let Edgar walk.
你认为你的搭档知道你跟内务部有联系吗？
Do you think your partner knows that you're with IA?
所以 我说对了
So, I'm right.
天啊
Jesus.
你知道吗 在这些事之前 我就盯上哈洛伦了
You know, I've been onto halloran since before all of this started.
内务部把他和过去几年的多起凶杀案联系在了一起
IA has him connected to multiple homicides going back years.
现在最新的竖锯谋杀案…
Now these latest Jigsaw murders...
之前我们带给你的三具尸体
The three bodies we brought you,
我们发现都和哈洛伦的案子有关
we found they're all mixed up in halloran's cases.
把他抓起来吧
Bring him in.
哈洛伦想要嫁祸给我
Halloran is trying to frame me.
- 我都不知道他凭什么针对我 - 是吗？
- I don't even know what he's got against me. - Really?
你知道你说过他搞砸了很多
You know you called him out for screwing up
十拿九稳的案子吧
slam-dunk cases.
还在媒体前说他是个白痴 两次
You said he was a moron in the press. Twice.
不 我是说他是个冲动的混蛋…
No, I said he was an impulsive asshole...
两次
Twice.
你还把克里斯汀的死算在他头上 不是吗？
You blame him for what happened to Christine, don't you?
听着 我不知道该怎么证明哈洛伦是竖锯的模仿者
Look, I don't know how to prove Halloran's the copycat.
是哈洛伦 就是他
It's halloran. It's him.
让我帮你理清楚案子
Let me help you build your case.
让我来帮你搜集证据
Let me get you proof.
让我去解剖埃德加·曼森
Let me open up Edgar Munsen.
我们把子弹和哈洛伦的枪做一下匹配
We match that slug to halloran's gun.
你用什么型号的手枪？
What kind of firearm do you use?
格洛克22
Glock 22.
大多数警察都用 除了哈洛伦 他用的17
Most cops do. Except halloran. He's got a 17.
9x19毫米巴拉贝鲁姆子弹 是格洛克17的
9x19 parabellum. That's a glock 17.
好吧
Okay.
我送你回家 你就待在家里等我电话
I'll take you home. You stay there until I call you.
我去抓哈洛伦
I'll get halloran.
埃尔 你到底在哪？
El, where the hell are you?
打给我 有急事
Call me, it's urgent.
天啊
Jesus!
埃尔
El!
我一直在给你打电话
I've been trying to call you.
- 我不知道那具尸体是怎么… - 不 不 不 没关系
- I don't know how that body got... - No, no, no. It's okay.
他们并没有怀疑你和我
They don't think it's you or me.
他们的注意力放在哈洛伦身上了
They have their sights set on halloran.
我找到了
I found it.
我想我知道游戏是在哪里进行的了
I think I know where the game is being played.
是一个农场
I found the farm.
- 太好了 赶紧打给警察 - 不要
- That's great, let's call a detective. - No!
哈洛伦是幕后黑手 我们不能信任这些警察
Halloran's behind this. We can't trust the cops.
什么？
What?
你想自己去看看这个游戏
You want to see this game for yourself.
你迷上这种东西了？
You get off on this shit?
洛根
Logan,
我们有机会拯救他们的性命
this is a chance for us to save lives.
那我们怎么对付一个连环杀人魔？
So, we're going take on a serial killer with what?
用我们聪明的脑袋？
Our cunning intellects?
还有这个
And this.
安娜
Anna!
别丢下我
Don't leave me!
安娜？
Anna?
安娜 我在流血 安娜
Anna,I'm bleeding out, Anna.
混蛋
Motherfucker!
安娜
Anna!
好了…
Okay...
安娜
Anna!
别丢下我 求你了
Don't leave me, please!
你好 安娜
Hello, Anna.
约翰？
John?
约翰·克莱默？
John Kramer?
发生什么了？
What's going on?
你们要玩一个游戏
You're about to play a game.
不
Oh, no.
不 你在干什么 约翰？你在干什么？
No. What are you doing, John? What are you doing?
这是终极测试
It's a final test.
我已经通过你的测试了
I already passed your test!
看看我的腿
Look at my fucking leg!
那不是你的测试 瑞安
That wasn't your test, Ryan.
如果你遵守游戏规则
And that wouldn't have been necessary
也不会变成现在这样
if you'd simply played by the rules.
但你一直都不喜欢遵守规则 是吧？
But you don't like rules, do you?
你想要我仁慈一点？
You want me to show mercy?
你从未有过一点点
You, who hasn't taken even a single step
真正的忏悔
toward confessing.
你不只是要对一个人的死负责
You, who is responsible not for one death,
而是三个人
but for three?
你从高中开始
Your life of reckless deceit
就肆无忌惮的欺骗
started in high school.
并且越来越糟
And only grew worse.
坐下 他妈的坐下
Sit down! Sit the fuck down!
他妈的放开我
Get the fuck off me!
你无数次的
You lied to the authorities
欺骗警察 瑞安
multiple times, Ryan,
把所有责任都推到司机身上
pinning the blame solely on the driver,
也就是你死去的好友
your deceased best friend.
你知道你对这个家庭做了什么吗？
Do you know what you did to his family? Hmm?
之后的几年你依然不知悔改
And you've only gotten worse over the years.
是我干的
I did it.
好吧 是他妈我干的
Okay, I fucking did it.
是我干的 但这是很久以前的事了
I did it, but it was so long ago.
我想活下来
I want to live.
我也想 瑞安
As do I, Ryan.
我们都想
As do we all.
但世事难料
But things happen.
如果当时不是住院医师
Were it not for a careless mistake
粗心大意犯了错误
by a resident at the hospital I was in,
我的癌症本应该更早被确诊的
my cancer could have been diagnosed a lot sooner.
仅仅是因为把X光片的名字弄错了
It was simply the wrong name on an X-ray.
本可以让我少受很多痛苦
Would've saved me a whole lot of hardship.
还有你 安娜？
And you, Anna?
我什么也没做 约翰
I didn't do anything, John.
你了解我的
You know me.
拜托不要这样对我
Please don't do this to me.
安娜和我是邻居
We were neighbors, Anna and I.
我的第一次化疗过程非常艰难 毫不夸张地说
My first chemo sessions were very difficult, to say the least.
安娜和她的丈夫马修非常善良
Anna and her husband, Matthew, were so kind,
给予了我很多帮助
so supportive.
我对此非常感激
I thank you for that.
为什么这样对我？
Why are you doing this to me?
那段日子非常美好 不是吗 安娜？
Those were better days for you, weren't they, Anna?
但你可怜的丈夫 马修就…
But your poor husband, Matthew...
我知道你们两个经常不合
I know the two of you didn't always get along.
但不得不忍受孩子的夭折这种悲剧 那真是…
But to have to endure that tragedy, the death of a child, that's, uh...
人生中的大不幸 不是吗？
One of life's greatest burdens, isn't it?
要是那晚他没有睡着
If only he hadn't fallen asleep that night,
他就不会翻身压到你们的孩子
then he wouldn't have rolled over and, uh,
使他窒息死亡
suffocated your baby.
事情就是这样 对吗 安娜？
That is what happened, right, Anna?
闭嘴
Shut up!
闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up!
我是说 真可怕 多么可怕啊
I mean, it's horrible. How horrible,
去接受这样一个事实
to have to live with such a thing.
它会让人发疯 不是吗？
It could make a person go mad, couldn't it?
你要对我们做什么？
What are you going to do to us?
我？
Me?
我什么也不会做
I'm not going to do anything.
你们必须要为你们的所作所为
You have to simply assume responsibility.
付出代价
For who you are.
就是这里
This is it.
你怎么知道是这里？
How do you know this is it?
塔克的养猪场
Tuck's pig farm.
这里因为奥耶斯基病毒的爆发被关闭了
It was shut down due to an outbreak of aujeszky's disease.
铁桶头的血液样本 猪病毒
Buckethead's sample. The pig virus.
这个农场是吉尔·塔克家的
This farm was in Jill Tuck's family.
她是竖锯的妻子
Jigsaw's wife.
现在还归她所有
Still is.
尽管这地方几年前就关闭了
Although the place was shuttered years ago.
但看起来好像还有人住在这里
Well, it looks like somebody's here.
你确定要这么做吗？
You sure you want to do this?
(基思·亨特警官)
哈洛伦 我是亨特 给我回电话
Halloran, it's Hunt. Call me back.
我们在哈洛伦家里 但他不在
We're at halloran's house, but he's not here.
- 你找到他的位置了吗？- 正在搜索
- You got a location on him? - Searching.
长官？
Sir?
我们得逮捕他 立刻
Okay, we need to bring him in. Now!
看这里
Check this out.
好多血迹
That's a lot of blood.
我敢打赌铁桶头就是在这里被斩首的
What's to bet this is where buckethead was decapitated.
是竖锯
It's Jigsaw.
竖锯已经死了
Jigsaw is dead.
是吗？
Is he?
求求你…
Please...
你让我做什么都行 约翰 求你放我走吧
I'll do anything you want, John, just please let me go.
拜托
Please.
你知道猪很有同情心的动物吗？
Did you know that pigs are highly compassionate animals?
如果看到其他动物 包括人类受苦
They show distress if they see any other animal,
它们就会很悲痛
including humans, suffering.
那你呢 约翰？
What about you, John?
你的同情心在哪儿？
Where is your compassion?
我们都在同一杆天枰上 安娜
We all have a thumb on the scale, Anna.
判别善良与罪恶
For good or for evil.
现在你在罪恶的那一端
You've been weighing in on the wrong side of the scale.
你们俩都是
Both of you.
如果你们想要自由
Now, if you want to achieve your freedom,
你们必须得学习
you have to learn.
你们得意识到你们一直都做反了
You have to realize that you've been doing it backwards.
所以…
So...
我会给你们一次机会
I'm gonna give you an opportunity
扭转回来
to turn it all around.
这是你们通往自由之匙
Here's your key to freedom.
一切都取决于你们
It's all up to you.
游戏很简单 好消息是
Now, the game's simple. The best ones are.
你们有一杆枪
You have one shotgun.
你们有一颗子弹
You have one shell.
正如我说的 一切取决于你们
Like I said, it's up to you.
你怎么能说竖锯没有死？
How can you say Jigsaw isn't dead?
他死了
He's dead.
他做过了尸检 还有坟墓
Autopsy was performed on his body and he has his own grave.
他没有死
He's not.
竖锯会永生
Jigsaw lives forever
通过他的追随者
through the work of his followers.
是你
You.
你一开始就痴迷于约翰·克莱默
You've been obsessed with John Kramer from the start.
那个网站
The website.
你做的陷阱机关
The traps you built.
很多人都痴迷于克莱默
Lots of people are fascinated by Kramer.
你知道我没有杀死铁桶头
You know damn well i didn't kill buckethead.
或者另外两个人
Or the other two.
- 那是谁干的？- 哈洛伦
- Then who did? - Halloran.
是你自己说的 子弹吻合
You said it yourself. The bullet matches.
他和所有受害者都有关联
He's connected to all the victims.
他就在你身后 放下武器
He's right behind you. Drop it.
放下 你们两个都放下
Drop it! Both of you.
快点
Now!
就是他
It's him.
- 就是他 - 放下
- It's him! - Go on.
- 不要 不要 - 快点
- Don't. Don't. - Come on.
- 快点 - 好的
- Come on! - All right!
- 不要 - 好的
- Don't. - All right.
好的 我把它放下
All right, I'm putting it down.
现在该你了 亲爱的
Now it's your turn, sweetheart.
快点 亲爱的
Come on, sweetheart.
- 不… - 快点
- No... - Come on.
把武器放下
Put it down.
不然我一枪崩了他
I'll blow his fucking brains out.
- 埃莉诺 - 对
- El. - Yeah.
这才是好姑娘
That's a good girl.
好了 你满意了…
All right. You got what you...
快跑
Run!
他想让我们射死对方
He wants us to shoot each other.
他想让我杀了你
He wants me to kill you.
不
No.
不 不 不要
No. No, don't!
不 别碰那个 你个疯婊子
No, don't touch that, you psycho bitch!
- 这是唯一的方法了 - 不 不要
- It's the only way! - No, no!
不 不 不要 好不好？
No. No. No, okay?
不 不 拜托不要 因为他想让我们这样
No. No, please don't. Because that's what he wants us to do.
- 明白吗？好好想想 - 同一杆天枰
- Okay? Think about it. - Thumb on the scale.
不 不 拜托不要 好不好？求你了
No. No, please don't. Okay? Please.
- 不 不 不要 - 善良还是罪恶
- No, no. No. - Good or evil.
- 不 求你不要 - 他就是这么说的
- No, please don't. - That's what he said.
让我们好好想想 好吗？好好想想
Let's just think about this for a minute, okay? Just think.
我们应该遵守规则 我们必须遵守规则
We're supposed to follow the rules, we have to play by the rules.
我通往自由的唯一方法
My only key to freedom
就是杀了你
is to kill you.
求求你
Please!
- 求你不要 不要 - 对不起
- Please don't! Please don't! - I'm sorry.
- 对不起 - 求你不要 不要
- I'm sorry. - Please don't, please don't.
反了…
Backwards...
他说我们一直都做反了
He said we've got it backwards!
不要
No!
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
不 不
No. No.
这是你们通往自由的钥匙
Here's your key to freedom.
不 不
No. No.
我们本来都能获得自由的 安娜
We could have been free, Anna.
对不起
I'm sorry.
哈洛伦
Halloran.
救命啊 有人吗
Help! Somebody!
救命
Help!
这他妈是什么东西 这他妈是什么？
What the fuck are these? What the fuck?
这些是他妈的激光切割器
These are goddamn laser cutters.
什么？什么？
What? What?
等等 等等 等等…
Wait, wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
等下 发生了什么？埃莉诺在哪？
Wait, what happened? Where's Eleanor?
- 哈洛伦 - 有人突然冒出来
- Halloran! - Someone came out of nowhere.
给我下药 把我放倒了
Drugged me. Knocked me out.
是的 我也是
Yeah, me too.
你们好 先生们
Hello, gentlemen.
你们来寻找游戏 恭喜 你们找到了
You came looking for the game. Congratulations, you found it.
你们是最后的两名玩家
You are the final two players.
这不可能
It can't be.
你也许能认出
You may recognize the device
你脖子上的装置 尼尔森医生
around your collar, Dr. Nelson.
这些激光切割器
These laser cutters
能像切奶酪一样切开你的组织和骨头
slice through tissue, and bone, like butter.
是这个世界上最锋利的刀刃
The most powerful blade on the planet.
你们都有机会活下来
You both have an opportunity to live.
你们需要做的就是忏悔
All you need to do is confess.
- 忏悔？- 就这么简单
- Confess? - It's that easy.
只要你们坦白自己该死的原因
If you admit to the reason that you deserve to die,
你们就可以免于一死
you can escape death.
我将洗耳恭听
I will be listening.
做出你们的选择
Make your choice.
你怎么还活着？
How are you alive?
你怎么可能还活着？
How are you still alive?
游戏将会选择你们其中一个
The game will select one of you
在60秒后开始
to begin in 60 seconds.
当然 除非你们有人主动选择先来
Unless, of course, someone chooses to go first.
我们都不要去碰按钮
Let's neither of us touch a button.
我们他妈一分钟后就要死了
We're both gonna be fucked in a minute.
我先来
I'll go first.
好吧
Okay.
等等 不 不 不 不
Wait! No, no, no, no!
不 不
No! No!
天啊 我没做错什么
Oh, god. I've done nothing wrong.
不 停下 停下
No, stop. Stop it!
- 停下 - 我忏悔
- Stop it! - I'd confess.
- 对 - 好 好 好 好的
- Yeah. - Okay, okay. Okay, all right!
好吧 约翰·克莱默 是我
All right, John Kramer! It was me!
是我 我搞砸了
It was me! I fucked up!
我弄错了你的X光照片
I messed up your x-rays!
我当时…我当时太粗心了
I was... I was careless.
我很抱歉
And I am sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我忏悔
I confess.
克里斯汀 非常对不起 宝贝
Christine, I'm so sorry, baby.
我应该在那陪着你
I should have been there for you,
但我没有
but I wasn't.
该你了 警官
Your turn, detective.
不 不 不 不
No! No, no, no!
我赢了 我赢了 我赢了
I won. I won. I won.
什么？
What? Huh?
该死
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit.
- 忏悔 - 好吧
- Confess. - Okay.
我干了一些坏事
I did some shitty things.
但是体制太腐败了 我试图纠正的
But the system's broken, i tried to fix it!
好吧 好吧
Okay! Okay!
我销毁了证据 我收受贿赂
I tampered with evidence. I took bribes.
我把无辜的人抓进去
I put innocent people away.
让杀人犯和强奸犯逍遥法外
Murderers and rapists walked.
人们因我而死
People died because of me.
无辜的人因我而死 是我做的
Innocent people died because of me. I did it!
这不可能
It fucking can't be.
什么？
What?
嘿 嘿 嘿…
Hey, hey, hey...
这…这是什么？
Wha... What is this?
你怎么…
What are you...
什么？你他妈在逗我吧？
What? Are you fucking kidding me?
洛根 你是…什么？
Logan, you're... what?
什么？嘿 什么 你…
What? Hey! What, you...
你和他一伙儿的？
You're working with him?
我就是他
I am him.
什么？
What?
在你的一点小帮助下
And with a little help from you,
没有人会怀疑了
no one will ever suspect it.
人们因我而死
People died because of me.
无辜的人因我而死 是我做的
Innocent people died because of me. I did it!
我不明白
I don't understand.
十年前 就在这个谷仓里
Ten years ago, in this very barn,
进行了一场游戏
a game was played.
据说 这个机关是约翰·克莱默
Supposedly, John Kramer designed this for a game
在其他那些人之前设计的一个游戏
that took place before all the others.
尸体一直还没被发现
The bodies were never found.
我知道这些 因为我是当时的游戏者之一
I know this because i was one of the players.
差不多十年前 竖锯抓我进了游戏
Jigsaw put me in that game almost 10 years ago.
我弄混了他的X光片
I mixed up his x-rays.
你得割伤自己
You need to cut yourself!
约翰认为我不应为无心之过而付出生命的代价
John decided I shouldn't have to die over an honest mistake.
他给了我第二次机会
He gave me a second chance.
所以 十年后的现在
So now, 10 years later,
我用你错案里的罪犯 重新布置了竖锯的游戏
I've recreated Jigsaw's game with criminals from your failed cases.
什么？
What?
我想让我的游戏和竖锯一样
I wanted my game to be identical to Jigsaw's.
所以我翻阅了你办过的案子
So I went through your cases.
找到了和原来的游戏里相似的人
Found players just like the ones in the original game.
我给了他们和十年前竖锯所给出的一样的选择
I gave them the same choices that Jigsaw did a decade ago.
竖锯的游戏里有五个人
Jigsaw put five people in his game.
我选了三个
I put in three.
你和我就是剩下的两个
You and I are the last two.
我想看看我是否能像他一样伟大
I wanted to see if i was as worthy as him.
一样有天分
As talented.
不…
No...
别这样 洛根
Come on, Logan.
拜托 可怜可怜我吧
Come on. Have mercy.
像你刚才那样可怜我？
Like you just had mercy on me?
你说开始我们的游戏？却按了我的按钮？
When you started our game just now? Pushing my button?
救你自己
Saving yourself.
什么？
What?
- 这…这不公平 - 公平？
- That... that's not fair! - Fair?
为什么埃德加·曼森被放出来了？
Why was Edgar Munsen free?
他是个杀人犯
He was a murderer.
但你包庇了他 因为他是
But you were protecting him because he was
你多年前的线人
your criminal informant, years ago,
所以你放了他
and you let him walk free.
埃德加·曼森杀了我的妻子
Edgar Munsen killed my wife.
你不…
You don't...
你不明白 这从没被证实过
You don't know that. It's never been proven.
这也不能让你的家人活过来
This won't bring your family back.
约翰·克莱默
John Kramer,
会给人一个赢下游戏的机会
gave people a chance to win the game.
一个选择
A choice.
操
Fuck!
你这个混蛋
You fucker.
你有选择
You have a choice.
喊叫 或者不叫
Scream, or don't.
洛根 洛根 洛根 洛根 嘿
Logan, Logan, Logan. Logan, hey,
听着 我能帮你 我能为你做很多事
look, I can help you. I can do things for you.
你能让我妻子回来吗？
Can you bring my wife back?
我说什么都没用了 对吗？
Doesn't matter what I say, does it?
我重置了一个竖锯玩过的游戏
I created a game that appeared to be run by Jigsaw.
(播放我)
(约翰·克莱默音频剪辑)
你好 埃德加
Hello, Edgar.
你将要玩一个游戏
You're about to play a game.
有五条人命在你手上
Five lives are in your hands.
按我说的做
Follow my instructions exactly.
我得做出选择 不是他们死就是我死
I got to choose who dies, them or me.
我他妈才不要死
I'm not fucking dying.
你用什么型号的手枪？
What kind of firearm do you use?
格洛克22 大多数警察都用
Glock 22, most cops do.
除了哈洛伦 他用格洛克17
Except halloran, he's got a 17.
9x19毫米巴拉贝鲁姆子弹 是格洛克17的
9x19 parabellum. That's a glock 17.
第一具尸体的指甲里提取到的
The blood under the fingernails of our first victim
是约翰·克莱默的血液
is John Kramer's blood.
有人会认为是竖锯做的
Some will think it's Jigsaw.
有人会怀疑你
Some will suspect you.
但没有人会怀疑我
But no one will suspect me.
我们得逮捕他 立刻
Okay, we need to bring him in. Now!
因为埃莉诺会提供我的不在场证明
Because Eleanor will provide my alibi.
太好了
Oh, yes.
十年前 我从战场归来 只有残破的身体
Ten years ago, I came out of the war a broken man.
竖锯重塑了我的人生
Jigsaw put the pieces of my life back together again.
他给了我人生的目标
He gave my life purpose.
我们永远不要沉迷于愤怒或复仇
We can never come from anger or from vengeance.
这是你教我的
You taught me that.
但这样就不会有正义
But then there will be no justice.
不 会有的
No. But there will.
因为我们会为死者发声
Because we'll speak for the dead.
我们一起建造了一个遗产
Together, we built a legacy.
现在 我要为那些被你这种人毁掉人生的人发声
Now, I speak for the lives ruined by people like you.
杀人犯 强奸犯…
Murderers, rapists...
他们的受害者都出现在我的手术台上
Their victims appeared on my table
都是因为你
because of you.
不 不
No. No.
不…
No...
我为死者发声
I speak for the dead.